## Marco Chávez, Senior Software Engineer

+525517049984, marcochavezf@gmail.com

LINKS	Portfolio, Github
PROFILE	Software engineer that has been programming for 15 years with 8 years of experience working on enterprise applications. Co-founded a startup company 6 years ago and enjoys building side projects that can provide value to other people.
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY	
Mar 2016 — Present	Sr. Web Developer, Primotus
	Primotus is a configurable workflow platform based on BPM and I'm currently working there as Sr. Web developer. My key responsibilities are: Maintain and redesign legacy code, fix bugs by design, create new modules,

review pull requests, and manage Google Play and App Store apps for beta testing and production release. Important solved problems:

- Improved iteratively the web apps to load elements (forms, views, tables, etc.) 150% faster in desktop and mobile devices.
- Adapted one of the system modules in order to use it as an internal error logger (using Kafka and Nest.js) saving hundreds of dollars per month in third-party services.
- Improved the data processing (using HTTP streaming and SQlite) to handle several MBs of server data in the mobile web app while keeping it running at a minimum of 30 Frames Per Second.
- Created one-step deployment (triggered every time changes are pushed to a Git branch) for mobile apps using Jenkins (Bash), npm scripts, and Ionic AppFlow.
- Implemented Store and Forward mechanism to process and sync off-line data with the server (resolving deltas with web sockets).
- Migrated a BPM modeler (using bpmn.io) for custom workflows.
- Designed agnostic components to be reused in both AngularJs and Angular9 projects.
- Created a map builder with custom graphic modules and custom map configurations using Leaflet and OpenStreetMap.

Jan 2014 — Feb 2016 Co-founder and CTO, Kangou

Kangou was an on-demand delivery startup that I co-founded 6 years ago. I built the first version of the platform using CakePHP, MySQL, and jQuery and then migrated it to MongoDB, Node.js, and AngularJs. Also, I built two mobile apps for Android and iOS (using Xamarin with MvvmCross), a web app to manage all the internal data (delivery orders, couriers registration, etc.) and a public REST API to integrate third-party business to our platform.

Feb 2014 — Jul 2014 Game Developer, Yogome

Yogome was an EdTech company and I worked there as a game developer. We developed two educative videogames using Corona SDK (Lua).

Nov 2012 — Nov 2013 Web Developer, P+P Energía

P+P Energía was a company specialized in consulting and contracting activities in the energy sector. Alongside with other 3 developers, we built a system to register, assign, and track tests for power stations. This project was built with CakePHP, MySQL, and jQuery.

**EDUCATION** 

May 2013

B.S. in Computer Science, Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios

Superiores de Monterrey (ITESM)

## PUBLISHED SIDE PROJECTS

Dec 2019 Last Active Positions

VS Code extension to track and navigate through the last active lines of code in a project.

Technologies: Typescript, VS Code API.

 $\underline{https://marketplace.visual studio.com/items?itemName=A we some-Reminder-Position.awe some-reminder$ 

Jul 2018 Timely

Chrome extension to see how much time you're spending on Facebook in real-time.

Technologies: Javascript, Chrome APIs

https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/timely/bfmbkfjklpkaogjlmcengklnloplijal

Jun 2018 Work-N-Flow

Minimalist Pomodoro timer.

Technologies: React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Firebase

https://worknflow.com

Nov 2017 AngularJs Profiler

Chrome extension to identify which code is executed in AngularJs web apps just recording user interactions.

Technologies: Javascript, Esprima

 $\underline{https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/angularjs-profiler/iffdmbfogminakpldcdpfgcchfgpflak}$ 

Feb 2014 Heady Kidz

A physics-based casual game with almost 10K downloads for Android devices.

Technologies: Java, AndEngine

Dec 2012 BASIC compiler

BASIC compiler built with F# and CIL (Assembly Language for .NET).

Technologies: F#, CIL .NET

**SKILLS** Expert Experienced Angular NodeJs SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL and Expert Experienced AngularJS SQLite)) Ionic Framework Expert Scala Skillful React Experienced SASS/CSS Experienced Expert Redux/NgRx

LANGUAGES English Highly proficient Spanish Native speaker